片名:终极面试
你是最棒的...
You deserve this...
绝对是
You do.
这是你努力的结果
You've earned it.
我无所不能 无所不能
I can do all things. All things.
快啊...
Come on...
快点 快点啊...
Come on, come on...
我是监考人
I am the Invigilator.
仔细听好我说的每个字
Listen carefully to every word I say.
我不会重复所说的话
There will be no repetition.
我不会为你们为了到这来所忍受的艰难经历而道歉
I won't apologise for the hardships you've endured reaching this room
因为那些压力和痛苦是必需的
'cause the pressures and pains were necessary.
在这种困难时期 适应能力是一项关键的特质
Resilience is a key attribute in these dark times,
如果你不能通过我们的筛选你也不会适合这项工作
and if you can't survive our selection process, you won't survive in the job.
许多优秀的应聘者在这个环节都被淘汰了
Many highly-qualified candidates tried to get this far and failed.
而你们却成功地留了下来
You have succeeded.
现在 最后的考验就在你们眼前
And now the final stage lies before you.
这是最后胜利前的最后一道屏障
One last hurdle separates you from your goal -
通过它 你就能成为我们中受人尊敬的一员
which is to join our esteemed ranks.
这项测试相对比较简单 但它却能决定
The test is simple in comparison, yet it will determine
谁能带着雇用合同离开这个房间
who leaves this room with a contract of employment
谁又会在离开后坐着大巴回家
and who leaves with the bus fare home.
通过这些考验 你们将了解到一些
Through these trials, you've gained some idea of the power
这个机构中有关权能的事 所以当我说
of this organisation, so believe me when I tell you
在这里没有法律 而只有我们的规则时 你们应该相信我
that there's no law in this room but our law.
这里只有我们定下的规矩
And the only rules in here are our rules.
只有一个问题向你们提出 你们只需回答出一个答案
There's one question before you, and one answer is required.
如果你试图与我本人
If you try to communicate with myself
或保安沟通 你将丧失竞争资格
or the guard, you will be disqualified.
如果你搞坏给你发的纸 不管是有意地还是无意地
If you spoil your paper, intentionally or accidentally,
你将丧失竞争资格
you will be disqualified.
如果你出于任何原因离开这个房间
If you choose to leave the room for any reason,
你也将丧失竞争资格
you will be disqualified.
有问题吗?
Any questions?
祝你们好运 女士们先生们
Best of luck, ladies and gentlemen.
我们给你们8个人80分钟时间
We're giving the eight of you 80 minutes.
你们用这80分钟来说服我们 让我们觉得你对我们来说是称职人选
80 minutes to convince us you have what it takes to join us.
这80分钟将决定你未来80年的命运
80 minutes to determine the next 80 years of your lives.
开始
Begin.
我还没写完呢
I'm not finished.
不 求你了 你不能这样啊! 正常的测试不是这样的啊!
No, please. You can't! This isn't a proper test!
求你了 让我重新开始吧! 给我个机会!
Please, I'll start over! Just give me a chance!
嘿...
Hey...
听着 听着 听着 都听着
Listen, listen, listen, listen.
他刚才宣布了什么不重要 你知道吧
It's not about what he said, you know.
重要的是他没宣布什么
It's what he didn't say.
"如果你试图与...
"If you attempt to communicate...
我本人或保安...
...with myself or the guard...
...你将丧失竞争资格 "
...you will be disqualified. "
- 他没说... - ...我们不能相互交谈
- He didn't say... - ...we can't speak to each other.
- 你们现在就在交谈啊 - 这是在搞终极脑筋急转弯还是怎么回事?
- Now you're talking. - Is this the ultimate mind-fuck or what?
- 有人想出答案了吗? - 没有
- Has anyone figured out the answer? - No.
答案不是重要的 重要的是问题
It's not about the answer. It's about the question.
- 问题是什么? - 我们还有74分钟把问题想出来
- What's the question? - We've got 74 minutes left to figure out.
如果这个问题只需要1分钟就能写出来我们才有74分钟把它想出来
If the answer takes one minute to write down.
如果要用73分钟把它写出来的话
If it takes 73 minutes to write,
我们就只有1分钟把它想出来
we have one minute to guess the question.
我们不用花太多时间写 我打赌肯定是你说的前一种情况
We're short on writing space. I'm betting it's the former.
我们得相互帮助
We've gotta help each other.
凭什么? 我们在相互竞争呢 为什么我要帮你来胜过我?
Why? We're in competition. Why should I help you to beat me?
当我们回答问题时可能是竞争对手
We may be in competition to answer the question,
但是我们在想出问题时得合作
but to establish the question we have to cooperate.
他们希望我们会相互合作 是吧?
They expect us to cooperate, don't they?
你希望什么?是不是你将得到这份工作
What'd you expect, you're gonna win this job,
然后拿着这份工作带来的丰厚报酬
with all the rewards that come with it,
而这些只因为你给他们交出了答案?
by giving them a little simple written answer?
事实与意见? 比较与对照!
Facts and opinions? Compare and contrast!
那可不是他们想要的结果
They're not looking for that.
这样的工作需要的是主动性
A job like this needs initiative,
观察能力...
observation...
协调能力
.. interplay.
- 团队合作 他说的对 - 我们可是面临着巨大压力啊
- Teamwork. He's right. - We're in a stress scenario.
搞得人稀里糊涂的 还搞倒计时
A confusing, time-critical situation
这肯定是为了测试我们的智商和适应力而设计出来的
designed to test our intelligence, and resilience.
- 为了将我们中最糟糕的人踢出去 - 也许是选出最棒的
- To bring out the worst in us. - Or the best.
我们应该相互帮助直到需要竞争的时候
We help each other until the playing field is open
然后哥们就各顾各的 没别的意思 姑娘们
then it's every man for themselves, no offence, girls.
- 都同意吧? - 好
- Are we all agreed? - Yes.
同意
Agreed.
- 来吧 甘地大叔 - 我的名字不是甘地 朋友 我叫...
- Let's go, Gandhi. - My name isn't Gandhi, friend. It's...
别在这说名字 反正不说真名
No names in here. Not real ones, anyway.
他们没在纸上写名字肯定是有原因的 对吧?
They're not written on this for a reason, isn't it?
那我们就用绰号吧
We'll use nicknames, then.
- 好啊 这样就简单多了 - 我们已经有编号了啊
- All right, let's make this easy. - We already have numbers.
是啊 还有真人现实出场
Yeah, and visual.
你就叫"小黑"吧
You're Black.
我是"小白"
I'm White.
你是"小棕"
You're Brown.
她叫"金发女"
We've got Blonde here,
那是"黑肤女"
Brunette there...
...我想你该叫"暗肤女"
.. Dark, I suppose.
最后 非常有幸我们中有个"聋子"
And last as well as least we've got Deaf.
- 最后这个名太狠了点 - 哼 管他的
- Tough last round. - Yeah, whatever.
有反对意见吗?
Any objections?
你是说对你那恶心 迟钝 充满性别和种族观念的陈腔滥调吗?
Apart from your grossly insensitive sexual and racial stereotyping?
如果你不迟钝 你就不会在这了 宝贝
If you're the sensitive type, you shouldn't be here, love.
我要"小棕" 不要"甘地"
I'll take Brown over Gandhi,
希望我们现在做的事对我们真的有帮助
I guess we're talking about something that matters.
那就是你没有反对意见了
I'll take that as a yes.
还有什么是他没有禁止我们做的?
So, what else hasn't he forbidden?
他没有禁止我们站起来 是吧?
He hasn't forbidden us to stand, has he?
- 好 我想来回走动也是可以的 - 那有什么用?
- Well, l guess moving about is OK too. - What's that gonna achieve?
不知道 小棕 不过坐着对我们也没什么好处 对吧?
I don't know, Brown. But sitting wasn't getting us anywhere exciting, was it.
会不会问题已经写出来了 只是我们看不到?
What if the question is written down but we just can't see it?
我也是这么想的! 多谢帮我说出来!
That's what l'm talking about! Thank you!
- 你是说像用隐形墨水那种东西写出来的? - 或者是像水印那样
- You mean like invisible ink? - Or a watermark.
- 有这个可能性 - 很有可能是这样 要不然问题在哪?
- It's possible. - It's probable. Where else would it be?
我们得用什么东西让它显现出来 比如通过光照发现
We'd need something to reveal it. Like light.
- 你说的"对" - 这些是卤光灯
- Right. - Those are halogen.
那些不是卤光灯
Those aren't.
灯又不咬你 你自己去啊
They won't bite, you know.
他们不会搞的这么简单 是吧?
They're not gonna make it that easy, are they?
时间不等人 他们能搞的有多难?
We're on the clock. How hard can they afford to make it?
会不会这铅笔不是用来写答案的?
What if the pencil isn't just for writing the answer?
会不会用它能让问题显现出来?
What if it reveals the question too?
会不会是用它把纸涂黑 就像涂印记纸那样?
By shading the page, like tracing paper?
- 试下嘛 金发女 - 不行 记得他说的吗?
- Try it, Blonde. - No. Remember what he said.
如果你搞坏给你发的纸 不管是有意地还是无意地...
If you spoil your paper, intentionally or accidentally...
你都将丧失竞争资格
.. you'll be disqualified.
有谁知道他说的把纸搞坏的确切定义是什么?
Is anyone certain they know what his definition of spoiling is?
我们得搞定麻烦 都想想办法啊
Look, let's crack this. Throw out some ideas.
会不会问题就藏在纸里
What if the questions are hidden in the paper,
但我们每个人得写出不同的答案呢? 他说...
but each of us has to write a different answer? He said...
只有一个问题向你们提出 你们只需回答出一个答案
There's one question before you, and one answer is required.
那个意思并不是说给我们的问题都是相同的
That doesn't mean it's the same question for each of us.
可能会有8个不同的问题和答案
There could be eight different questions and answers.
如果我们能找出其中一个问题 剩下的也都能找出来了
If we find one question, we can find them all.
没必要 也许8个不同的问题
Not necessarily. Not if our eight individual questions
只能用8种不同的方法找出来
can only be revealed using eight different methods.
也许我们根本就用不着合作
Perhaps we're not meant to cooperate at all.
这个观点我"喜欢"
I like that idea.
或是只有1个问题 印在我们中某一人的纸上
Or there's only one question, printed on only one of our sheets.
- 那我们就得要合作... - 你们消停会 来做个测试吧
- Then we'd need to cooperate... - Time-out for some testing.
大家都到灯这来
Everyone up to the light.
我跟你说了 他们不会那么简单就让我们得手的 是吧?
Look, I told you they're not gonna make that easy, are they?
除非你想给我们大家的灵机程度做个排名 小白
Unless you want to make a list of our brainwaves, White,
我觉得我们不应该争来争去的
I say we cross a few off as we go.
好吧
Fine.
让我来吧
Allow me.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂 和我们一起来搞啊 聋子!
Yeah, join in any time, Deaf !
你不喜欢闲聊 是吧?
You're not one for small talk, are you?
来 给我
Come.
放松点 看完就还给你!
Relax, you'll get it back !
瞧 我说过的 我们可以不考虑光照的因素了
Alright, like l said, l think we can strike light off the list.
光是有波谱的
Light is a spectrum.
有些光我们能用肉眼看到
There's light we can see,
但有些光我们肉眼是看不到的
but there's light we can't see.
比如紫外线 红外线 X光
Like ultraviolet, infra-red, X-rays.
好 如果我们看不到它 又怎么把它找出来呢?
Look, if we can't see it, how are we supposed to find it?
发光源肯定是能看到的 就算它发的光我们看不见 对吧?
The source must be visible, even if the light isn't. Right?
找一下这些灯的开关
Find the light switches.
没有 反正在这找不到 还有...
There aren't any, not in here anyway. And...
如果你出于任何原因离开这个房间...
If you choose to leave the room for any reason...
...你将丧失竞争资格
...you'll be disqualified.
肯定有办法让这些灯开启关闭的啊
There must be some way to trigger these.
这是个紧急状况备用灯
This is emergency lighting.
那我们来制造出一个紧急状况
So let's create an emergency.
那太冒险了
That would be very risky.
- 这总比什么都不做风险小对吧? - 他说的对
- It's less risky than doing nothing, isn't it? - He's right.
如果我们这样做又失败了 就不能恢复原状了 会变成漆黑一片的
If we try this and fail, we can't go back. Blackout.
我们举手表决吧
We vote.
把那些灯也搞掉
Those too.
好啊! 太好了!
Nice! Very nice!
蓝调酒吧 您想来点什么?
Touch of blue, what you wanted?
这是暗光灯
This is black light.
信用卡公司用这种灯来让他们的安全标记显示出来
The kind credit card firms use to reveal their security symbols.
哦 我们没有应聘去VISA信用卡公司真是太可惜了!
Yeah, what a shame we didn't apply to work for Visa!
- 我们的赌博可能会有回报的 - 是有回报
- Our gamble might have paid off. - It did pay off.
只不过不是以你想要的方式回报
Just not in the way you wanted.
你一有动作 房间就会做出反应
You acted, and the room reacted.
我们已经与房间有了互动 我们应该继续进行
We've entered a dialogue now, we should keep going.
是啊也许应该...也许不应该
Yeah, maybe... Maybe not.
不好意思 你说这会出现肉眼看不见的光
Sorry, it was invisible light you said you wanted here.
但是现在这光我看得他娘的非常清楚
'Cause this looks pretty fucking visible to me.
这种光的科学术语叫"近紫外线光"
Scientific term for it is "near-ultraviolet".
是没起作用 但总应该试试吧
It didn't work, but it was worth trying.
哦 如果情况不改变 我们走出这个房间时都会被烤成非洲鸡了
Well, if nothing else we'll come out of this with great tans.
我们得把这些灯也搞掉
We've got to knock these out too.
这些灯带的上端槽里没有发光
The top hives of these strips aren't lit.
来看啊
Look.
红外线 这是另一种办法
Infrared. The other option.
- 它也能照出什么吗? - 它比紫外线更少见 但也能照出东西
- That exposes something too? - It's less common than UV, but yes.
艺术历史学家们用它来反射出
Art historians use it to make reflectograms
油画作品底层的轮廓草图
of the sketch outlines beneath paintings.
如果发给我们的纸里也有好几层的话...
If there's a hidden layer in our papers...
小心点
Carefully.
我猜这回是不是应该叫"近红外线光"了?
Let me guess, "near-infrared"?
好了 大家再试一次
All right, everyone, try again.
- 有人发现什么吗? - 没有
- Anyone? Anything? - No.
屎啊!
Shit!
我们现在能不能别再往灯上想了?
Now can we please get off the lighting?
如果你提出个更好的办法就行
If you can provide a better alternative.
什么办法都行啊 我们已经浪费了4分之1的时间了
Any alternative. We've burned a quarter of our time already.
也许这公司是小日本开的 这个测试是考我们折纸手工水平的
Perhaps the company's Japanese-owned and this is an origami exam.
你请便吧 反正搞坏了也是你的纸
Be our guest. That sheet is yours to spoil.
对啊 不过只是"你的"纸
Yes, it is, but only your sheet.
- 那只是张纸而已 - 不 它现在不只是张纸了 是吧?
- It's a piece of paper. - No, it's more than that now, isn't it?
它现在是个实验材料
This is experimental material.
- 如果你搞坏了... - ..."你的"纸
- If you spoil... -.. your paper.
- "你的"纸! - ...你将丧失竞争资格
- Your paper! -.. you will be disqualified.
这不是我的纸 这是她的
This isn't mine. This is hers.
"这不公平啊!"
"It's not fair" !
现在她走了 所以...
And she's gone. So...
我涂...
Tracing...
哦 恭喜 金发女 你的主意也是屁作用都没有
Well, congratulations, Blonde. Your idea sucks too.
这些东西可能都是用来分散我们注意力的 知道吧
This could all be a distraction, you know.
我们可能没发现某些显而易见的东西
We could be missing something obvious.
好 好 好!行了!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! All right!
灯没起作用 发光管也没起作用...
Light does not work, LED does not work...
液体!
Liquid!
哦 对吔...
Oh, yeah...
好的
Right.
舔这些纸 在上面弄上口水 把它弄湿 好吧?
Lick it, spit on it, get it wet, alright?
如果问题是水印在纸上的 我们得用些液体让它显示出来
If the question's watermarked we may need some liquid to bring it out.
- 你手上拿的纸怎么弄? - 你不会想知道的 伙计
- What are you doing with yours? - You don't wanna know, mate.
- 我们当然想知道 - 好 那你过来看吧
- Actually, we do. - Well, you can come and watch.
你还可以帮我把纸拿好 如果你喜欢的话
You can hold it for me too if you like.
- 虽然我更喜欢"金发女"来干这事 - 真恶心
- Though I'd prefer it if Blonde did. - That's disgusting.
"用任何必要的方法" 对吧 兄弟?
"By any means necessary", right, brother?
如果我们能这么做 那我觉得我们就应该做
If we can do it, I say we should.
你那么做不可能让问题显示出来的 尿是无菌的 你都可以喝它的
That's not gonna bring the question out. Urine's sterile. You can drink it...
- 真希望你会喝下去 - 好极了 撒尿比赛啊
- Wish you would. - Great. A pissing contest.
有东西显示出来吗?
Anything?
- 现在还不好说 纸都变黄了 - 把它拿起来让我们看看
- I can't tell yet. lt's all yellow. - Hold it up and let us see.
嗯 如果你借我个手套 我就拿
Well, if you'll lend me a glove, l'll oblige.
唉 我没什么主意了
Well, l'm running out of ideas.
这么容易就放弃了?小黑 还剩57分钟呢 你真丢脸
Giving up so easily, Black, with 57 minutes on the clock? You should shamed of yourself.
你知道吧...
You know what...
我们俩个能闭嘴吗?我们这还有人要考虑问题呢!
Will you two shut up? Some of us are trying to think!
终于 他说话了
At last, he speaks.
他是法国人
He's French.
- 你们看? - 这有人会说法语吗?
- Vous voyez la? - Does anyone here speak French?
你们看
Vous voyez la?
你能看见吗?
Can you see?
你看...?
Vous voyez...?
仔细看
Regardez bien.
- 你能看到这些东西吗? - 看见什么东西?
- Can you see it in there? - See what in there?
看见什么?漂亮的颜色?
See what? Pretty colours?
- 你自己 - 你自己
- Vous-meme. - Yourself.
你 你看
Vous vous voyez.
它让你看到了你自己
It shows you yourself.
- 是啊我们一共6个自己呢 - 别烦他 他又没对你做什么
- And then there were six. - Leave him alone. He's done nothing to you.
是啊他对我们解决问题屁主意都没出 疯子!
He's done nothing for me either or any of us flatten the matter. Nutter!
必须要清楚的看下去
Toujours y voir clairement est primordial.
去看明显是最关键的步骤
To see clearly is all.
好了 你够了吧 萨特! (法国哲学家 此为反讽用法) 行吧?
All right, that's enough out of you, Sartre! alright?
狗屁哲学家
Fucking philosophers.
感谢上帝 这是个实干家的世界 而不是空想家的世界
Thank God that this world belongs to the doers, not the thinkers.
既然我们在提各种假设 我也提一个
Since we're proposing grand theories, let me advance one of my own.
这不是个测验
This is not an exam.
在常识上来说不算是
Not in the conventional sense anyway.
瞧瞧我们这些人
Look around.
你再也找不到其它更有代表性的团队
You couldn't ask for a more representative group
有资格来进入这最后的考验了
to qualify for the final stage.
4个男人和4个女人进入到这个房间
Four men and four women entered this room,
我们分别有不同的文化和人种背景
all from different cultures and ethnic backgrounds,
而且都拥有不同的技能
possessing a healthy mixture of skill-sets.
真是太方便了 布局的太好了
How convenient that is. How staged.
你什么意思?难道是他们专门做了个局让我们几个聚在一起?
What are you saying? They rigged the tests to bring us together?
他说的是某种团体互动能力实验
Some kind of experiment in group dynamics.
- 你到底在说什么? - 我的意思是这只是个游戏
- What are you talking about? - I'm saying this is a game.
- 他们在我们身上下注赌输赢 - 好 他们是谁?
- And they're betting on us. - Right and who is "they"?
这公司的董事会
The board.
我猜他们这会正在看着我们呢
I guess they're watching us right now.
他们以前可能都是风险投资商
They'll be ex-VCs mostly.
也许他们终止了与托管公司的合作 在他们意识到
Probably left the incubator when they realised
他们投资的小企业已经赚了大钱之后
their little start-up had struck the mother lode.
搞这种权力把戏对他们来说肯定很爽 我敢肯定
It wouldn't get any sweeter than this, I'm sure.
于是他们就进入了公司的董事会
So they joined the board,
搞到了丰厚的股份
secured some big fat stock options
这样他们就有权利来享受点娱乐活动了
and bought themselves the right to have a little fun...
把我们当傻子一样玩
With us.
你觉得他们除了搞这种把戏就没别的事可做了?
You don't think they have better things to do with their time?
比如做什么?
Like what?
在他们那个位置上 钱不再是最重要的了
At their level, money ceases to be the prime motivator.
找刺激才是他们想要的
It's risk they live for.
他们都很优秀 就像我们一样
They're type A's, like us,
他们投资的公司把他们训练成这样的
and just as they were trained by their investment companies,
他们现在就在主意上押宝呢
they're still betting on ideas today.
在我们身上押宝
Ours.
谁会把问题解码出来 谁会一败涂地
Who'll decipher the question, who'll come up empty and fold
谁又会在重压下崩溃
and who'll crack under pressure.
你说的可能是错的
You could be wrong.
也许只有监考人在监视我们
It could just be the Invigilator behind there.
我们打赌?
Wanna bet?
如果我是你 我就不会和他打赌
I wouldn't, if I were you.
小棕说起话来像个赌徒 因为他本来就是个赌徒
Brown talks like a gambler because he is one.
而且还是个职业赌徒 对吧?
A professional. Aren't you?
你呢 暗肤女 是个心理医生
And you, Dark, are a shrink.
心理学还是精神病学专家? 我搞不清两者的区别
Psychologist or psychiatrist? I forget the difference.
精神病专家是给病人开药帮他们控制情绪的
Psychiatrists dispense drugs to control mood.
我是个很棒的人类行为学学生
I'm a qualified student of human behaviour.
那你应该明白我刚才说的那些事
Then you should know what I'm talking about.
拥有权力的好处就在于可以滥用权力
The point of having power is to exercise it in all its forms.
- 我们在这只是任人摆布的对象 - 那又怎么样? 说这些没用的!
- We're pawns of the Gods in here. - So? This changes nothing!
是啊...
Yeah...
这游戏总是要有人赢的嘛...可能会是团队的胜利
Games are played to be won...as a team.
是 也可能是某一个人的胜利
Yeah, or as individuals.
如果对他们来说唯一取胜的方式是让我们失败的话 那就没戏
Not if the only way for them to win is for us to lose.
我是说我们所有人都失败 你们想过这个可能性吗?
All of us. Have you thought about that?
你错了
You're wrong.
没有什么"他们"在监视我们
There is no 'them' watching us.
应该是这公司的CEO在监视我们
The CEO is hands-on.
他得事无巨细的处理对公司来说很重要的事
He micro-manages anything of importance to his company.
而这个筛选程序很不寻常
And this is no ordinary selection process.
因为我们都很特别
We're special.
如果说除了监考人外有谁在监视我们的话 那肯定就是他了
If anyone's back there besides the lnvigilator, it's him.
这公司其他所有人都只是他的马仔而已 董事会成员也一样
Everyone else is a secretary in his structure, even board members.
因为他就喜欢别人对他俯首贴耳
That's how he likes it.
你怎么会知道这些的?
How do you know all this?
我们在浪费时间
We're wasting time.
只剩50分钟了 我们在找问题上一点进展都没有
There's 50 minutes left, we're no closer to finding the question.
我觉得找出问题和我刚才问她的话有关系
Somehow I suspect my question relates to the question.
回答我的问题
So answer me.
- 你怎么会知道那些情况的? - 和你知道董事会的办法一样啊
- How did you learn that information? - Same way you learned about the board.
我才不了解董事会的事呢 我只是做了个有理有据的推测而已
I don't know anything about the board. I made an educated guess.
而你...你知道谁是CEO 他都喜欢什么 你怎么知道的?
But you...you know who the CEO is and what he's like. How come?
- 你怎么可能不知道呢? - 我们怎么可能知道? 我们都是猎头公司选来的 对吧?
- How come you don't? - How could we? We were headhunted, weren't we?.
- 怎么? 你不是? - 当然不是!
- Why? Weren't you? - Of course not!
我听说这有空缺的职位就应聘了 我还以为大家都和我一样呢!
I heard there was a vacancy and applied. I thought we all did!
你是说你想在这个公司就职
Are you saying you wanna work for this company,
通过层层选拔终于走到如今 而你却对公司没一点了解?
jumped through every hoop to get here but you don't know who they are?
我知道工资和福利 行了吧? 还有详细的职位描述
They listed salary and benefits, OK? the job description detail,
"世界500强公司之一 以高度的责任感
"A high level of responsibility in a Fortune 500 company
出产应用于核心服务行业的高端技术" 我就了解这些 行了吧?
manufacturing state-of-the-art technology in a core service industry". that's it, All right?
- 你就没想多了解点? - 当时不准问问题的
- You didn't wanna know anymore than that? - The deal was no questions asked.
是啊 我们相信了他们的工作人员说的话
Yeah, we trusted their agents,
任何人听到这种介绍都会跳槽来这的...
anyone would've done the same in our position...
任何...想往高处走的人都会的
Anyone with...balls.
- 你们都是应聘来的? - 是啊
- You all applied? - Yeah.
如果这公司名气这么大 还用做什么广告啊?
If this job is so prestigious, why they have to advertise?
- 他们没打广告 - 我们是通过我们的渠道了解到招聘信息的
- They didn't. - We have our sources.
- 看样子来竞职的人有点多了 你觉得呢? - 我不会对人多不多说什么的
- Looks like we're outnumbered, do you? - I wouldn't cry about it.
- 你现在相比我们来说可是占尽了优势 - 你不说我还真不知道我有什么优势呢
- You've the edge over us now. - I really had your word with on that.
你是被请来的 对吧? 他们是请你来竞争职位的
You're wanted, aren't you? They invited you to apply.
要我说的话 因为你竞聘的积极性这么高 我们才是处于不利地位的人呢
I'd say we're disadvantaged because you showed the initiative to apply.
我们现在在这方面都被你甩在后面了
We're behind the curve now.
告诉我们你都知道些什么 从全面的职位描述开始吧
So tell us what you know, starting with a complete job description.
- 我们应聘来的不了解那方面的情况 - 哦 是吧 你觉得我们会相信吗?
- We don't have that information. - Oh, right, you expect us to believe that?
关于职位的事情我们知道的绝对没你多
We don't know any more about the job than you do.
我们只知道些关于这个公司的事 相信我
We just know about the company and, believe me,
他们公司最低工资都比其它公司最高工资都高
the worst job with them beats the best anyone else can offer.
他说的对 他们是什么公司 谁是CEO 他都有什么成就
He's right. Who they are, who the CEO is and what he's achieved,
这就是我们被告知的情况
that's all you need to know.
好 那把这些情况说给我们听听
All right, so tell us about it.
我给你提供点线索吧
I'll give you a clue.
10年前 世界各地有许多本来很健康的年轻人
10 years ago a lot of healthy young people around the world
都得病了 病得奄奄一息
got sick and started dying.
这件事你可能早就知道了
You may have read about that.
然后 一位医学研究者研制出了一种病毒抑制剂
Then a medical researcher patterned a virus suppressant.
半年的时间 就把死亡率减半了
The mortality rate halved in six months,
而如今 他办的公司已经是最大的
and now his company is the biggest player
全球性医药企业了 营业额超过200亿美元
in the global health industry with a turnover of $20 billion
股市市值为600亿美元
and a market capitalisation of $60 billion.
如果这个公司是个国家的话
If it was a nation state,
它将成为全球第8大经济体
it would rank as the world's eighth largest economy.
而到明年则会升到第6大经济体
Next year that rises to sixth.
这你可能也早就听说了
You may have read about that too.
是Biorg公司!
Biorg!
80分钟...
80 minutes...
...决定你未来80年的命运
...to determine the next 80 years of your lives.
还记得监考人说的这句吧?
Remember?
他们做的事就是让人的寿命变长
Longevity is what they do.
转基因药物 基因疗法 微创手术应用
Antisense drugs, gene therapy, microsurgical applications.
瞎扯! 他们公司去年宣布中止雇用员工了!大家都知道
Bullshit!They announced a hiring freeze last year! Everyone knows that.
那只是公开说说而已 私下里...他们又开始招兵买马了
Publicly that's true. Privately...they're expanding again.
为将来的大项目做准备
Gearing up for a big push of some kind.
他们肯定是研制出了新的特效药
They've found a cure.
肯定是这样!
They must have!
生产部和市场部
Manufacturing and marketing
将会扩员3倍 这都是为了新药上市做准备
would triple in size for the roll-out.
那样我们所有人都会在这找到合适的职位!
There'd be jobs for all of us!
- 我们还不知道情况是不是这样呢 - 但这是有可能的 对吧?
- We don't know that. - But it's possible, isn't it?
如果情况属实的话 得到FDA的批准文件得多久? 你知道吗?
How long would FDA approval take?if it's true, do you know?
- 那方面的情况我不了解 - 等等
- That's not my field. - Hold on.
你为什么对这些事这么感兴趣? 你有什么事想告诉我们吗?
Why are you so interested? Is something you want to tell us?
如果你的意思是问"我是不是也得了那种病?" 回答是"没有"
If you're asking "Am I infected?", White, the answer is "No".
- 我很健康 - 不过你认识的某个人肯定得了那种病了
- I'm clean. - But someone you know isn't.
我们认识的人里肯定都有得那病的 要不然怎么会称其为"全球性流行病"
We all know somebody with the virus, that's why they call it a pandemic.
很好的托词
Nice evasive manoeuvre,
但我们实际上说的是你 还有你到这来的真正原因
but we're actually talking about you and the real reason you're here.
好的...那么 是你的什么亲戚得病了呢?
Yeah...So, what relative is it?
是你妈? 还是你爸? 你妹妹?
Is it your mom? Your dad? Your sister?
是我的男友 行了吧? 他没钱用抑制剂
It's my partner, OK? He can't afford suppressants,
而抑制剂卖给本公司员工是有折扣的 你现在高兴了吧?
but they're discounted to employees, are you happy now?
还有谁是为了寻求救济来这的?
So who else is a charity case here?
是啊 就算有人是也不会公开说的 对吧?
Yeah, you wouldn't speak up, if you were, would you?
没人会想像她一样在这监视器前自毁前程
You don't want to commit career suicide on camera like she just has.
这还得谢谢你的帮助呢
With a little help from you.
她的境况又不是我造成的 我只是把它给曝出来了而已
I didn't create her situation, I just exposed it.
无所谓啦 如果她有了正确的答案
Doesn't matter. If she gets the answer right,
一样会被录用的 和其他人一样
she's still hired, like rest of us.
真的? 谁说的? 他们?
Really? Says who? What...them?
- 如果我没记错的话... - 这里只有我们定下的规矩
- If memory serves me correct... - The only rules in here are our rules.
他们可以取消所有人的竞争资格 好不好?
They can disqualify everyone! OK?
他们可以做任何想做的事 而我们却对此毫无办法
They can do whatever they like and we can't do a thing about it.
所以啊...恭喜你!
So...congratulations!
你在没打破任何规则的情况下出局了
You've just disqualified yourself without breaking any rules.
他不会把你赶出去 但你已经被淘汰了 宝贝
He won't kick you out, but you're dead in the water, honey.
死翘翘了哦
Dead in the water.
别听他乱说 我们会一起通过测试的 知道吗?
Don't listen to him. We'll get through this together, alright?
谢了 不过我不需要你的帮助
Thanks, but I don't need your help,
因为我的境况不是我的弱点 而是我的优势所在
because my situation isn't a weakness, it's a strength.
我肯定以他们的聪明 肯定会了解到这一点的
I'm sure they're smart enough to realise that.
如果我能和公司的CEO谈谈的话
And if l could talk to the CEO
我会向他说明 治疗我的男友只会让
I'd assure him the treatment my partner needs will only deepen my commitment
我在以后的工作中对公司更加忠诚
to his organisation for years to come.
你真的以为公司的CEO在通过监视器看着我们吗?
You really think he's behind there?
他长年累月就待在办公室里
He's lived behind walls for years.
他核心圈子里的人自从公司股票首发(IPO)后就没再见过他了
No one outside his inner circle has even seen him since the IPO.
如果他想招个助理的话
If he wanted to hire an assistant,
他应该会用这种办法的
this is the way he'd do it.
你在搞什么?
What are you doing?
证明我的价值 你们也许都没主意了 但我还有呢
Proving my worth. You may have run out of ideas, but I haven't.
- 别和他说话 - 我又没打算和他说话
- Don't even try talking to him. - I'm not gonna talk to him.
是他那有东西吸引你过去呢 还是他想让你过去找他?
Is there anything in there, or is he happy to see you?
看看找到了什么?
What have we here?
只有这个?
Is that all?
加热也许会让纸有反应
Heat may have an effect
如果这些纸是经过化学处理了的
if the papers have been chemically treated.
- 如果我们从下方给其加热的话... - 不是加热和化学反应 小黑
- If we warmed them from beneath... - It's not heat and chemicals, Black.
只是化学反应而已
It's just chemicals.
你说的是什么意思啊? 水?
What are you talking about? H2O?
水涂纸上已经试过了! 刚才用口水试的!
We already tried H2O! It's in all our bodily fluids!
咱们又不知道这上面的管子是接到哪的
We don't know what these pipes connected to?
喷什么液体下来都有可能啊!
You could pump any liquid through them!
试试吧 "爱因斯坦"
Come on, Einstein
天啊 你说的对
Good Lord, you're right.
这些根本就不是红外线
These aren't infrared at all.
这些是安全灯! 标准而普通的安全灯!
They're safelights! Common standard-issue safelights!
我们这是在暗房里! 这间屋子是个大暗房!
We're in a darkroom! This room is a great big darkroom!
- 这些纸肯定是照片纸 - 那我们可以冲洗这些纸让它们成像吗?
- And this must be photographic paper. - Meaning we can develop it?
做梦呢吧...洗照片可不是一个步骤就可以完成的
You hope... Developing photos isn't a one-stage process.
- 那得用化学药水洗 再用修正药水... - 那是洗彩色照片时用的方法
- It takes chemical baths, fixing agents... - For colour photography.
要让黑字从白色背景中显示出来
To pull black letters from a white background
只需要有显影液就行了 其它什么都不用
all you need is developing fluid, nothing more.
我们开始干吧
Let's do this.
我入伙
I'm in.
就算她说的对
Even if she's right,
我在想化学物质喷到我们身上会不会不好啊?
the idea you want to think is a chemical shower a bad idea?
喷的劲不会太大的 我担心的是他们会不会让我们出钱修被损坏的东西
It'll be diluted. I doubt they want to hire damaged goods.
不过还是把眼睛 鼻子和嘴巴遮起来比较好
But covering your eyes, nose and mouth may be wise.
恐怕不止应该只遮这几个地方吧
They're not the only things worth covering.
我就知道 事情有眉目了你就现身了
That's it, join in at last.
你是聋子又不是哑巴 嗯?
You're deaf but not dumb, eh?
别担心 宝贝 我来想办法
No worries, love. Let me.
行了
Let's go.
- 怎么样? - 得等会才能有效果
- Well? - It'll take a few moments.
我的纸呢?
Where's my paper?
谁看到我的纸了?
Has anyone seen my paper?
不!
No!
你个杂种! 杂种!
You bastard! Bastard!
你怎么能这么做? 你怎么能这么做? 杂种!
How could you? How could you? Bastard!
你刚才做了什么?
What did you just do?
做的是我必须做的事
What l had to.
我真应该把你打得晕死过去!
I should punch you lights out!
- 小黑 你做什么了? - 这和小黑做了什么没关系
- Black, what did you do? - It's not what he did.
- 这和他说了什么有关系 - 什么?
- It's what he said. - What?
他刚才说了"熄灯" 看 开灯!
"Lights out". So...lights up!
- 这样好多了 - 关灯
- That's better. - Lights out.
开灯 这是声控的
Lights up. Voice-activated.
- 他们在逗我们玩呢 - 这声控系统还真棒 是吧?
- They're playing with us. - Great, isn't it?
- 从现在开始大家都得注意下自己说的话 - 还有自己做的事
- And from now everybody watch what you say. - And do.
这可真是祸从天降啊
Up one minute, down the next.
这上面写不成了 是吧?来 试一下吧
Can't write on this anymore, can you? Go on, try.
别试了
Don't then.
你饿吗 伙计? 喂 你饿不饿啊?
Are you hungry, mate? Oi, are you hungry?
我饿啊 我真饿死了
I am. l'm really hungry.
不过这没有加工快餐的机子 是吧?
There's no snack machines in here, though, are there?
继续啊 把这纸扯碎...喂!扯碎它!
Go on, rip it up...Oi! Rip it up!
- 嘿!我刚才给你说什么了? - 她让你别烦他 小白
- Hey! What did I tell you before? - She said leave him alone, White.
- 对 拿着 撕碎它! - 小白 你能不能停下来!
- Yes, hold it, tear it up! - White, will you stop!
撕碎它! 撕啊!
Tear it up! Tear it!
我警告你最后一次 小白!
I won't tell you again, White!
这就对了 好孩子 继续啊
That's it, good boy. Go on.
继续啊 再来 再来
Go on. More, more.
放到你嘴里去
Put it in your mouth.
麻烦你
S'il vous plait!
这下只剩咱们5个人了
And then there're five.
- 说你是杂种真是在夸你
- "Bastard" doesn't do you justice.
是你说我们在找出问题前应该合作的!
You said we should cooperate until we discovered the question!
我那是谎话!
So I lied!
我撒谎了 那又怎么样?
I lied. So what?
说谎又不违反规则 对吧?
Lying is not against the rules, is it?
反正我说什么你们也不会听 更不会同意或遵从我的意思
Anyway, you don't have to listen to me, let alone agree or obey.
你们应该感谢我 你们每个人都应该感谢我
You should thank me. All of you should thank me.
我把竞争范围缩小了 你们这些剩下的机会不就变大了
I've just narrowed down the field, so your odds improve.
没有问题摆出来 机会有个屁用!
Odds mean nothing without the question in front of us!
还有 你别指望我们会帮你找出问题
And you can forget about any more help from us in finding it.
我才不用你们帮忙呢 到时候你会发现是你需要我的帮助
I don't need your help. I think you'll find it's you who needs my help.
知道为什么吗? 因为我已经把它想出来了
You know why? Cause I figured it out.
哦 真的? 把问题想出来了? 问题是啥? 说给我们听听
Oh, really? The question? What is it, then? Tell us.
为什么要说给你们听?
Why should I?
因为如果你不说 我会打的你说
Because if you don't, I'll beat it out of you.
你真是垞屎 小白 刚进这屋我就闻到你身上的屎味了
You're full of shit, White. You have been from the start.
你屁都没想出来
You don't know anything.
他想出来也不会告诉我们的 因为他是个自恋狂
He wouldn't tell us if he did, 'cause he's a narcissist.
他看不起我们
He despises us.
说的跟真的一样啊 宝贝
Sticks and stones, love.
我打赌你肯定对所有的男生都是这个看法 是吧?
I bet you say that to all the boys, don't you?
我只对有自恋病态人格的人持这种看法
Only the ones with Narcissistic Personality Disorder.
你这种人有9种个性特征:
There are nine character traits to look for:
自大 好大喜功 觉得自己是独一无二的
arrogance, grandiosity, a belief in one's uniqueness,
急于得到权力 获得成功
a preoccupation with power and success,
过于渴望被崇拜 希望得到认可
an excessive need to be admired, a sense of entitlement,
缺乏替人着想之心 还有嫉妒和压榨他人的双重倾向
lack of empathy and the twin tendencies to envy and exploit others.
做为临床诊断来说 有5种以上特征就是病人了
For clinical diagnosis, a patient must exhibit five of these.
- 你是绰绰有余了 - 你可以再加个第10种特征
- You tick enough boxes. - You can add a tenth to that list.
"有看穿你身边所有屁话的能力
"A tendency to see through all the bullshit surrounding you,
还能从屁话中脱颖而出 "
and rise above it. "
- 这一条我自认了 - 我来帮你认清楚吧
- I'll tick that box myself. - Let me tick it for you.
- 你那样做可真是"聪明"啊 - 这样做很有必要
- That was smart. - That was necessary.
我们可能会用得上他呢 他只是个资源而已
We may need him. He's a resource, nothing else.
你不喜欢某人的话 要智取他
You don't like someone, Outwit them.
他是我们团队的敌人 还是个让人分神的东西!
He's an enemy of the group, and a distraction!
你不来帮我一把吗?
You gonna give me a hand?
-1 2...
- One, two...
你搞什么?
What are you doing?
确保他醒过来后不会再制造任何麻烦
Ensuring that he can't cause any more trouble when he wakes up.
- 然后再让他被淘汰掉 - 这看起来可不太公平啊
- And taking him out of the game. - That hardly seems fair.
这是他该得的报应 只不过报应来的有点狠罢了
He sacrifices his right for payment. Forward a bit.
看到了吧? 我把他放倒了然后我们又一起合作开了
See?I put him down and suddenly we're cooperating again.
他是个大嘴巴
He's a talker.
我们还能再往狠点干
We could go further than this.
她说的对
She's right.
我们可以把他拖到门那 把他推出去
We could carry him to the door and slide him out.
他把8个中的2个人搞出局了 为什么我们不能把他也搞出局?
He ejected two of us, why shouldn't we eject him?
- 叫正义也好 如果你喜欢叫因果报应也行 - 你不会原谅别人吗?
- Call it justice, or karma if you prefer. - You don't believe in forgiveness?
- 我情愿以后再原谅他 - 那你所倡导的合作精神呢?
- I'll be happy forgive him afterwards. - And your gospel of cooperation?
我宽容任何人 但决不宽容对别人不宽容的人
I'll tolerate anyone, except the intolerant.
这是我最爱的圣经语录...
Those in favour...
一半对一半
Fifty-fifty.
那我们各行其事吧
To each his own.
好了 如果你不能抛开个人好恶来想这事 那你考虑下自身利益吧
OK, if you can't think selflessly about this, think selfishly.
监考人说过...
The Invigilator said...
如果你因任何原因离开这个房间
If you choose to leave this room for any reason,
你将丧失竞争资格
you'll be disqualified.
他没选择离开房间 是吧? 是你替他做了选择
He's not choosing to leave, is he? You're choosing for him.
这样的话 你也有被淘汰的危险了
Which puts you at risk too.
来吧 小白 把你的纸搞坏 现在轮到你了
Go on, White, spoil yourself. It's your turn.
画啊
Make your mark.
瞧 我们的时间只剩不到半小时了
Look, we have less than half an hour left
而我们还是不知道问题
and we still don't know the question.
他宣称自己知道问题
He claims to know the question.
闭上鸟嘴!
Shut up!
我得吃药 药在我口袋里
I need medication, it's in my pocket.
- 什么药? - 跟你有什么关系?
- What kind of medication? - What does it matter?
是口服药 行了吧? 每隔1小时就得吃一次 现在已经到点了 好吗?
It's a pill, all right? I need to take it every hour, on the hour, OK?
- 我现在就得吃 - 每隔1小时 现在吃?
- That's right now. - Every hour, on the hour?
只有一种情况下才会用这种治疗方法
Only one condition is treated that way.
你也得了那种病 是吧?
You're infected too, aren't you?
这可真是太公正了 这种公正太美妙了
That's more than justice. That's poetic justice.
如果你不信 松开我的胳膊 我他妈就能拿到药片了!
If you don't believe me, untie my arms, so I can fucking take the pill!
- 快啊! - 别做梦了
- Go on! - Nice try.
真是可悲啊
It's pathetic, actually.
好吧 你来拿 你拿给我 药在我左边口袋里
alright, take it yourself. Get it for me yourself. It's in my left pocket!
- 你想怎么样我都照做 快先帮我拿药 - 真的?
- I'll do what you want. Just do it. - Really?
那先告诉我们问题是什么
Tell us what the question is then.
好吧 把药拿出来我就告诉你
Alright, get the pill and I'll tell you.
快啊! 快他妈拿药给我!
Come on! Fucking do it!
快 在我左边口袋里
Go on, it's my left pocket.
快啊再找找 药就在那呢 快啊
Go on, try again, it's in there. Go on.
药他妈的到哪去了?
Where the fuck is it?
你们有人把药拿走了! 有人他妈的把我药拿走了!
One of you has taken it! One of you has fucking taken it!
这可不是闹着玩的!
This isn't funny!
你们都知道病人没吃抑制剂会怎么样!
You know what happens when you don't take suppressants!
不省人事 抽搐 休克 昏迷 死亡
Unconsciousness. Convulsions. Shock. Coma. Then death.
我们非常清楚会怎么样
We know exactly what happens,
而这一系列过程要持续几个小时呢 不是几分钟的事
and the process takes hours, not minutes.
听着 伙计 我会自动退出竞争的 好吧?
Listen, mate, I'll be out of it for good, alright?
这是以你之道还施你身
A taste of your own medicine.
- 别这样 别这样 - 往好的方面看 兄弟!
- Don't do it, don't do it. - Look on the bright side, brother!
如果你开始抽筋 我们才知道你说的是实话啊
If you start to convulse, we'll know you're telling the truth.
那我们将会乐于帮助你
Then we'll gladly help you.
看样子你的愿望得到满足了
Looks like you've got your wish.
只是暂时的而已
For now.
必须得用什么办法得把他收拾一下
He had to be dealt with one way or another.
如果他是这公司派来的奸细 我一点都不会觉得奇怪
I wouldn't be surprised if he was a plant all along.
他就是他们想要的 用来煽动我们情绪的那种人
It's the kind of thing they'd do to stir up our internal dynamics.
煽动我们相互敌对
To set us against one another.
如果他真是奸细 收拾了他主动权就在我们这了
If so, we've seized back the initiative.
也许是你掌握了主动权
Or you have.
他还没聪明到能做名奸细
He isn't smart enough to be a plant.
而你在某些方面却更合适做奸细
But you on the other hand.
你认为她和他们是一伙的?
You think she's one of them?
别搞笑了! 我说了我是个心理学学生!
Don't be absurd!I told you l'm a psychologist!
你声称自己只是个心理学学生 而不是实习医生
You claimed to be a qualified student of psychology, not a practitioner.
我也学过心理学 我学的是逆向心理学
I've studied psychology too, and reverse psychology.
有什么方法能掩盖你在这场闹剧中的真实身份
What better way to hide your true role in this farce
比指责在扮演你的角色的其他竞争者更有效呢?
than to accuse another candidate of playing your part?
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
业余心理学知识对一个赌徒来说是件有用的工具
Amateur psychology is a useful tool for gamblers,
而你取得心理学的学位
but a degree in the subject
那可真是开始职业生涯的良好基础 你可是高级人力资源
sounds like the perfect foundation for a career in, say human resources.
但你却到这来 这很说不通 对吧?
You're on the wrong side of the glass, aren't you?
- 他才是想要操控的那个人... - 也许你看起来团队合作性很好
- He's the one who manipulated... - Maybe you work as a team.
他只会耍耍嘴皮子而已 而你...
He's got the mouth, but you...
...却知道那么多有关Biorg制药公司的事
...know an awful lot about Biorg Pharmaceuticals.
- 我说了我是应聘来的! - 我们也是啊
- I told you I applied! - So did we.
- 我做了相关调查的! - 我们也做了的!
- And I do my research! - So did we!
我们中可能是有奸细 不过不可能我们全都是
Anyone of us could be plants, but not all of us.
至少应该有一个竞争者是为了求生活而来参加这个测试的
At least one candidate has to be genuine for the test to be viable.
- 那肯定就是我啊 - 我也是啊
- That would be me. - And me.
我说的意思是我们现在无法证明谁是或不是奸细
My point is we can't prove anyone's guilt or innocence,
所以试着去证明只会浪费时间
so it's a waste of time to try.
如果我们之间不能保持信任与合作的话 那我们都会完蛋的
If we can't maintain trust and cooperation, we're through.
信任是要用行动来获取的 MM
Trust has to be earned, sister.
本来我们也没有理由相互信任的
We never had cause to trust each other in the first place.
信任只是一种选择 我们可以选择进行合作 如果必要的话
Trust is a choice. We can choose to keep cooperating, if necessary.
- 我觉得是有这个必要的 - 我们没有其它的选择
- I think it's necessary. - We have no other option.
信任别人让我紧张
Trust makes me nervous.
- 我情愿选择去证实 - 你在干什么啊?
- I prefer proof. - What are you doing?
- 放开我! - 你疯了吗?
- Get off me! - Are you insane?
- 小棕 你为什么要这么做啊? - 因为我喜欢胜出!
- Brown, why are you doing this? - Because I like winning!
现在把真象说出来吧 暗肤女
Now tell us the truth, Dark.
求你们了 你们说过我们应该相互信任的!
Please, You said we have to trust each other!
现在你们就看着他在这审讯我 什么也不做吗?
Now you're gonna stand there while he interrogates me?
看样子他们不会帮你的 他们也想知道真象啊
Looks like it. They wanna know too.
继续死不认帐只会浪费时间
Further denials will only waste time.
坦白的话我就放了你 我保证
Confess and l'll release you. I promise.
好吧 我是为他们工作的 但他们没派我到这来!
OK, I work for them, but they didn't put me in here!
我是通过内部消息知道这个职位在招人 然后就象其他人一样来应聘了!
I heard about the job internally and applied like everyone else!
你和我们可不一样
Not everyone.
把我们想知道的所有事都说出来
Tell us what we want to know.
我什么都不知道怎么可能告诉你什么事啊!
I can't tell you anything because I don't know anything!
公司人力资源部(HR)不管CEO办公室的人员配备 CEO亲自招聘他下面的人!
HR doesn't cover the CEO's office, he hires his staff personally!
我没说谎! 我也象你一样想往公司高层爬!
I'm not lying! I wanna step up as badly as you do!
我说过的 信任在这一文不值
Like I said, trust is a devalued currency in here.
那我怎么样才能向你证实我说的话呢?
What proof can I possibly give you?
你看 很有趣啊...
You know, it's funny...
一件简单而无害的东西
how something so simple and inoffensive
比如这张纸
as a piece of paper,
如果被居心不良的人拿着
when placed in the wrong hands
就会成为一件致命的武器
can become a deadly weapon.
而加工这武器的原料却来源于树
All from one slice of a tree.
- 你做什么? - 做还剩余有时间的情况下我必须要做的事
- What are you doing? - What has to be done while the time is remaining.
你要刑讯逼供吗?
You're gonna torture me?
- 帮帮我! 求你们了! - 小棕 你要干什么啊?
- Do something! Please! - Brown, what are you doing?
- 我很清楚我在干什么 - 你是说你以前也这样干过?
- I know what I'm doing. - You mean what, you've done this before?
- 是 以前在军队服役时干过 - 我还以为你是个职业赌徒呢
- In the services, yeah. - I thought you were a gambler.
军人都是赌徒
All soldiers are gamblers.
瞧 我知道大腿内侧的肉肉特别地敏感
See, I find the flesh of the inner thigh especially sensitive.
- 混蛋! 别碰我! - 住手吧! 应该还有其它办法让她交待的!
- Fuck you! Get off me! - Stop this! This can't be our only option!
是 是有其它办法 但我喜欢用这办法
No, it isn't, it's mine.
看看这是什么啊?
What have we here?
看样子在我之前已经有人收拾过你了
It seems you got there before me.
怎么? 是因为在工作中还是在家里表现不好?
What, undervalued at work and at home?
你老爸不喜欢你?
Daddy didn't love you, hm?
我这是用你所心理学知识分析出来的 我分析的对不对啊?
Through your studied psychology to find out why, Tell me I'm wrong.
不 其实在我进一步考虑后 别回答我前面的问题 回答这个提问...
No, actually on second thoughts, don't answer that. Answer this...
- 问题是什么? - 我不知道!
- What is the question? - I don't know!
- 你在说谎! - 我不知道 我发誓!
- You're lying! - I don't know, I swear!
问题是什么?
What is the question?
这项测试的目的是什么?
What is the purpose of this exam?
你觉得如果我知道通过测试的方法是要对我刑讯逼供才能找出来
Do you think I volunteered if the only way for you to solve this was to
我还会自愿参加这个测试吗?
beat it out of me?
你这个爱找麻烦的家伙!
How fucked up are you!
只有20分钟了 这才是最麻烦的
With 20 minutes left, this fucked up.
好了 够了!
OK, enough!
别来插手
Don't interfere.
看在上帝的份上 她只是个女流之辈啊
For God's sake. This is a woman.
男女平等 小黑
Equal opportunities, Black.
你们人力资源部派你来时早就知道会这样 对吧?
HR wouldn't expect anything less, would they?
哦 对啊想办法让保安来帮你啊
Oh, by all means, ask him for help.
瞧 这不是针对你个人的
Look, it's nothing personal.
我们只是想知道你所了解的情况而已
We just need to know what you know.
小棕 别这么干! 肯定有其它办法去了解情况的!
Brown, don't do this! There must be another way!
我们需要的是确定无疑的结果
We need certainty.
而这样的结果只有通过施加难以忍受的痛苦得到...
The kind only unbearable pain can give...
我已经告诉了你我所知道的一切事!
I've told you everything I know!
求你了 住手吧!
Please stop!
...只有通过威胁才能得到答案
...or the threat of it.
她说的是实话
She's telling the truth.
不好意思
Sorry.
拿去
Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不是想看他抽筋吗 现在他开始抽搐了
You wanted convulsions, now you've got them.
你觉得他是装出来的?
You think he's faking it?
是真的抽了
It's genuine.
- 你怎么知道? - 我妻子就是得这病死的
- How do you know? - My wife, she died from it.
我也中了这种病毒 他没装
I'm a carrier. He's not faking.
就算是骗子有时也会说真话
Even liars tell the truth occasionally.
- 他得吃药 是吧? - 得尽快给他吃
- He really needs that pill, doesn't he? - Fast.
如果有谁拿了他的药 现在快点承认吧
If anyone took it, own up now.
好吧 如果我们相互都信不过的话 那只能相互搜身了
Alright, if we can't trust each other, we'll have to search each other.
没有
Nothing.
- 还有口香糖吗? - 不好意思 吃完了
- Got any gum? - Sorry. I'm all out.
真的?
Really?
军人都是赌徒
All soldiers are gamblers,
而赌徒又都是作弊者 我找到了
and all gamblers are cheats, I've found.
是通过你所说的格言找到的
Given the opportunity.
- 我算到了你可能会找到的 - 你和小白一样坏
- I took a calculated risk. - You're as bad as he is.
不 他比小白更坏 小白至少不会伪装自己
No, he's worse. There was never any pretence about White.
- 让我们从自身利益角度出发再好好想想吧 - 他就要死了 还要想?
- Let's think about it selfishly again. - While he's dying?
这可不是一己之利的事 这是谋杀!
That's not selfishness, that's murder!
死亡之前会昏迷的 对吧?昏迷时再吃药 也能恢复过来的
Coma comes before death, right?People recover from comas.
他这种状况不行的 他的状况太严重了 不可能恢复过来的
Not this kind. Sink too deep and it's irreversible.
而这个药里的成份能象肾上腺素一样重新激活他的心脏
But that pill mimics an adrenaline shot to the heart.
如果想救他的话 就得马上给他吃药
If you're gonna do it, do it now.
你忘了你是怎么说他的了吗?
Have you forgotten what you said about him?
我们又不是要放开他 只是救他的命 让她给他喂药!
We're not releasing him, we're saving his life, now let her go!
我恐怕不能让你这样做!
I'm afraid I can't do that!
能看见 就是够不着!
I can see it, but I can't reach!
我来试试
Let me try.
显然神灵们也同意我的观点
Obviously the Gods agree with my risky assessment.
他不省人事了吗?
Is he unconscious?
他快不行了!
He's lapsing!
咱们得把他带出去进行治疗
We have to carry him out for treatment.
Biorg公司会理解我们的做法的 相信我
Biorg will understand. Trust me.
你到底帮不帮我?
Are you gonna help me?
好 你们可以毫无良心地看着他死 我不行
Fine, you can live with his death on your consciences. I can't.
他在出血! 这是怎么回事?
He's bleeding! What does that mean?
不知道 我以前没见过这种情况 不过这绝对不是好事
I don't know, I haven't seen this before. But it can't be good.
- 救救他啊 小黑! - 怎么救? 我又不是医生!
- Do something, Black! - Like what? I'm not a doctor!
请救救他啊!
Help him, please!
你们没看到他快死了吗?
Can't you see he's dying?
不! 我是这的员工! 我在这公司里工作的!
No! I work for you! I work here!
这药还真象你说的那样起作用啊
You weren't wrong about that pill.
嘿...
Hey...
- 如果你能听到我说的话 点下你的... - 一群混蛋
- If you can hear me, nod your... - Fuckers.
我也感染了这种病毒 兄弟
I have it too, brother.
是嘛 别指望我感谢你
Yeah, well, don't expect me to thank you.
你得感谢她...
You have her to thank...
而不是谢我
.. not me.
嗯 真希望她给我做人工呼吸来救我而不是给我吃药
Well, I would've preferred the kiss of life.
我敢说你做人工呼吸肯定很在行 对吧?
I bet you're good at that, aren't you?
噢
Wow.
留下了4个淘汰了4个
Four down and four to go.
只剩10分钟了
And only 10 minutes on the clock.
真是激动人心的测试啊!
It's exciting!
我刚才感觉到你从我身上拿药了 知道吧
I felt you take it, you know,
这房子无法同时容纳咱们2个人
It's a room not big enough for both of us,
要的就是你这股狠劲 小棕
That's the spirit, Brown.
如果你能记得我拿走你的药
If you remember me taking it,
那你也应该能记得你给我们的许诺
you'll remember the promise you made us.
金发女把药给你吃了
Blonde gave you the pill as requested.
现在你应该兑现你的承诺了
Now give us what we asked for in return.
- 你说的是问题吧? - 问题是什么?
- The question? - What is it?
问题藏在哪?
Where is it?
你还是没明白 是吧?
You still don't get it, do you?
那还是让我来给你说清楚吧
Let me spell this out for you.
根本就没有问题!
There is no question!
明白了吧?
Alright?
从一开始就没有问题!
There never was one!
哼 反正没有你们所想找的那种问题
Well, not the kind you're looking for anyway.
这就是你不想说出来的信息?
That's what you've been holding back?
- 这就是你的小秘密? - 是哦
- That's your big secret? - Uh-huh.
你知道监考人说了什么
You heard the lnvigilator.
只有一个问题向你们提出 你们只需回答出一个答案
There's one question before you, and one answer is required.
只有一个问题! 你的意思是监考人说的是谎话?
There is one question! You're calling him a liar?
当你排除掉所有的不可能因素后
When you've eliminated the impossible,
剩下的肯定就是真象了 对吧?
whatever's left has to be the truth, don't they?
不管结果多么不可信 但它就是真象
No matter how crazy it seems.
这项测试就是所谓的问题!
This test is the question!
而我们就是答案
And the answer is us.
- 我们都是答案 - 答案 复数?
- We're the answers. - Answers, plural?
- 如果我没记错的话... - 你们只需回答出一个答案
- If I recall... - One answer is required.
- 答案应该是单数的 - 对啊
- Singular. - That's right.
我们中只能有一个成为答案
Just one of us.
你敢!
You wouldn't dare.
哇哦! 哇哦!
Whoa! Whoa!
- 哇哦! 大家都冷静点 好吧? - 同意!
- Whoa! Everybody calm down, yeah? - Seconded.
好吧 好吧 好吧
Alright, alright, alright.
- 你不会向我开枪的 - 我抢枪不是为了射你的!
- You're not gonna shoot me. - I didn't take it to shoot you!
我是为了阻止你抢到枪向我们开火!
I took it to stop you from using it on us!
让我告诉你我是怎么想的
Let me tell you what I think.
我也认为我们就是答案 不过是我们一起 做为一个团队一起成为答案!
I think we're the answers too. All of us together, as a team!
我走进这房间是还觉得我们大家都会通过这个测试的
I think we'd all passed when we walked in here.
而我们的所作所为却让我们失去了本来得到的东西
All each of us can do today is lose what we've already won
这都是因为大家的私心重 愚蠢和急功近利!
through selfishness, stupidity and impatience!
聋子说的对
Deaf was right.
在这我们只看我们想看到的东西
We see what we want to see in here.
你是个好斗的人 所以你所想的就是
You're a fighter so you all can think about
成为我们中唯一的胜出者
is being the last man standing,
但是他们根本就没说过只招聘一个人
but they never said there was only one position available.
好 我只看我想看到的 小黑
Yeah, I see what I want to see, Black.
而你只听你想听的话 对了吧?
And you hear what you want to hear, alright?
但你回答下我的问题 兄弟!
But answer me this, brother!
什么样的公司会不清楚自己有多少空缺职位?
What corporation doesn't know how many positions it's got available?
什么样的CEO居然决定不了自己要1个还是8个助理?
What CEO can't decide whether he wants one assistant or eight?
CEO办公室只有一个空缺职位 你知道的
There's only one job going in his office, you know that,
你说的那些只是你的想象而已
And the rest is fantasy.
小白 别靠上来!
White, stay back!
为了这份工作杀人不值啊
This ain't worth killing for.
你好象不是这样想啊 是吧?
You seem to think it is, is it?
- 为了这份工作值得你去死吗? - 把枪放下 小黑
- Worth dying for? - Put the gun down, Black.
是你先想去抢枪的 现在我是箭在弦上不得不发了!
You started this, now it's in play!
- 我们不可能再把枪放回保安的枪套里了 - 那就把它扔出门去吧
- We can't put it back to the holster. - Throw it out the door then.
这样做也不会违反规则啊
That won't break any rules.
来吧 射我啊
Go on, shoot me.
来啊 爆我头 来啊
Go on, shoot me in the head, go on.
- 看 你就不是个杀人的料 对吧? - 别再靠近了!
- See? You can't fight who you are, can you? - Don't!
指纹验证系统啊
Fingerprint ID.
不要啊!
No!
好的
OK.
好吧 好吧
OK, OK.
告诉我们你要怎么样
Just tell us what you want.
我想要单独胜出!
I want to be alone!
你想让我们把我们的纸都毁掉?
You want us to spoil our papers?
自行丧失竞争资格?
Disqualify ourselves?
好吧
OK.
我们俯首称臣就是了
We'll take those odds over the alternative.
你胜出了
You win.
我没办法让我的这个同伙护送你出去了 他得要用手帮我呢
I can't let my partner escort you out, we just became friends.
你自己走出这个房间怎么样?
How about you walk out instead?
你们都出去 一个一个来
Each of you. One by one.
从你开始
Starting with you.
快啊 我们时间不多 走吧!
Come on, we ain't got all a day! Let's go.
这个破公司很配你个烂人
They deserve you.
该你了
Now you.
快点
Come on.
- 别犯傻了 小黑 - 你不会开枪的
- Don't be stupid, Black. - You won't shoot.
我不会中弹的
I'll be missed.
你和我一样都得了那种病
You're sick like me.
你死在这的话 他们会有合理的解释来掩盖真象的 明白?
Your death will be explained away, OK?
房间外面的人不会关心真象的
No one outside this room even cares.
他们自己还有事要操心呢
They've got problems of their own,
比如避免被病毒感染
like avoiding the infection themselves.
你的良心会不安的
Your conscience will haunt you.
如果我有良心的话才会不安嘛
You're assuming I've got one.
我走 我弃权
I'll go. I'm through with this.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
别哭 亲爱的
Don't cry, darlin'.
反正你也不过只是这的一个过客而已
You were a passenger in here, anyway.
- 你自己把事搞砸了的 - 我还救了你的命呢
- You fucked your way to the top. - Then I saved your life.
哼 人人都会犯错的 我恩将仇报也只是犯了个小错而已
Well, anyone can make a mistake.
关灯!
Lights out!
开灯!
Lights on!
必须继续清楚的看下去
Toujours y voir clairement est primordial.
去看明显是最关键的步骤
To see clearly is all.
噢?
Well?
你说会有一个胜出者的 这个胜出者就站在你面前!
You said there's one answer and you're looking at him!
我做了能做的一切! 我制造这儿发生的所有事端
I've done everything! I made everything happen in here,
而她什么都没做!
and she's done nothing!
我是胜出者! 我才是你想要的人!
It's me! I'm the one you want!
我是你想要的人!
I'm the one you want!
如果你试图与我本人或保安沟通...
If you try to communicate with myself or the guard...
...你将丧失竞争资格
...you will be disqualified.
我就知道 事情有眉目了你就现身了
That's it, join in at last.
你是聋子又不是哑巴 嗯?
You're deaf but not dumb, eh?
只有一个问题向你们提出 你们只需回答出一个答案
There is one question before you, and one answer is required.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
- 答案? - 这就是你不想说出来的信息?
- Answers? - That's what you've been holding back?
- 这就是你的小秘密? - 你还是没搞明白 是吧?
- That's your big secret? - You still don't get it, do you?
问题是什么? 它藏在哪?
What is it? Where is it?
- 你是说问题是什么吗? - 这项测试的目的是什么?
- The question? - What's the purpose of this exam?
- 问题到底是什么? 告诉我们啊! - 和你有什么关系?
- The question? What is it? Then, tell us! - What does it matter?
你觉得他在监视我们?
You really think he's behind there?
他长年累月就待在办公室里
He's lived behind walls for years.
你怎么知道这些情况的?
How do you know all this?
你什么意思? 难道是他们专门做了个局让我们几个聚在一起?
Are you saying? That they rigged the test to bring us all together?
你有什么事想告诉我们吗?
Is there something you want to tell us?
- 这只是张纸而已 - 哦 这可不只是张纸 对吧?
- It's a piece of paper. - Well, It's more than that, though, isn't it?
如果我们根本就无法看到它 怎么能把它找出来?
If we can't see it, how are we supposed to find it?
会不会问题已经写出来了? 只是我们看不到而已?
What if the question is written down? We just can't see it?
会不会这也能让问题显现出来呢?
What if it reveals the question too?
他们不会搞的这么简单就让我们得手的 对吧?
They're not gonna make it that easy, are they?
那他们能搞的有多难?
How hard can they afford to make it?
有没有人已经想出答案了?
So has anyone figured out the answer yet?
答案不重要 重要的是问题
It's not about the answer, it's about the question.
问题是什么啊?
What is the question?
问题是什么?
有疑问吗?
Any questions?
没有疑问
No.
这就是你向我们提问的那个问题的答案
That's the answer you wanted to the first question asked of us.
那也是我唯一的提问
The only question asked of you.
- 我也几乎错过了答案 - 几乎?
- I almost missed it too. - Almost?
实际上 我们很高兴今天招到了人
As it is, we're happy to be hiring someone today.
我还没决定来不来这个公司呢
I haven't accepted yet.
如果你不想要这份工作的话 你刚开始就不会应聘了
You wouldn't have participated if you didn't want the job.
那是没有发生这些事之前
That was before. Before all this.
现在测试结束了 我也要提问
Now it's over, I have questions.
- 提问? - 是 不止提一个
- Questions? - More than one.
问吧
Ask.
你看起来不像这个公司的CEO啊
You don't look like him.
任何体面的人都能在股东和媒体面前冒充CEO
Any suit can play the CEO for shareholders and the media.
而我们公司的创始人不是个商人
Our founder isn't a businessman.
- 他对虚名不感兴趣 - 太可惜了
- He has no interest in fame. - That's too bad.
- 他刚才的演技都可以得奖了 - 谁说他那是演出来的?
- That was some performance. - Who said it was a performance?
我们公司的创始人是个科学家 革新者
Our founder is a scientist, an innovator.
他对要来公司与他共事的人的要求是很高的
He's very particular about those he invites to work with him,
特别是这次的招聘决定是他做过的最重要的招聘决定
especially when it comes to the most important hiring decision he's ever made.
重要到可以为此杀人?
Important enough to kill for?
你怎么会觉得他死了呢?
What makes you think he's dead?
在研发针对那种病的特效药时
While searching for the cure,
我们意外地发现了某种超强的东西
we stumbled upon something far more powerful.
急速细胞再生...
Rapid cell regeneration...
...通过口服药来实现
...in a pill.
这种药能根除那种病毒 并能治愈其它难以治疗的基因疾病
It eradicates the virus and other stubborn mutations.
- 这是有魔力的子弹啊 - 这能拯救成千上万人的生命
- The magic bullet. - The gift of life for millions.
不过这也带来了意想不到的两难局面
Such a breakthrough creates unanticipated dilemmas.
而这种局面任何人都无法单独应付
Too great for any one man to bear.
人们会非常需要这种药
People are gonna need this product,
而我们的生产能力又有限
and we can only make so much at a time.
这就需要有个明智人来做出艰难的决断
Tough decisions are gonna have to be made by a wise administrator,
这个人必须同时具备倾听意见和
someone who combines a listening disposition
关注细节的能力
with attention to detail
以及对下属的关照
and compassion for her fellow man.
如果你还对这份工作感兴趣的话...
If you are still interested...
他回来了
Il est revenu.
他...
He is...
...活过来了
.. risen.
让我们开始合作吧
Let's get it started.